Dominic Palmer

dominicpalmer.org github.com/dominicpalmer dominicpalmer @outlook.com

SUMMARY

Mobile: On request Location: Brighton, UK Age: 26

An Imperial College Applied Mathematics MSc graduate and passionate software engineer, with 3 years industry experience spanning full SDLC software development, data science, statistical programming and machine learning for research and development.

LANGUAGES & LIBRARIES

- C# | C++ | Python | Bash/Shell | SQL Server | JavaScript | HTML | CSS | SCSS | LATeX
- .NET Core | Dapper ORM | DbUp | Swagger/OpenAPI | RESTful MVC Web APIs | MSTest | xUnit
- Standard Template Library | GoogleTest | GNU Make | NumPy | Pandas | Matplotlib | scikit-learn

Tools & Workflows

- Git (CLI) | GitHub | Azure DevOps | Travis CI | Jira | Confluence | Rally | Trello | Slack
- VSCode | Neovim | Tmux | Zsh | Visual Studio | JupyterLab | TeXstudio | Linux | Windows
- Agile | Scrum | Waterfall | CI/CD | Unit Testing | TDD | International teamwork (UK, USA, Ireland)

Experience

Applied Systems

Brighton, UK; Belfast, NI (remote)

Nov. 2020 - Present

Junior Software Engineer

- o SchemeRater: In a team of two, we developed and deployed a set of microservices that calculate insurance premiums in real time according to pricing models specified by insurers. (C#, .NET Core, SQL Server)
- Applied RDS Web Portal: Created an internal web portal that provides management functionality for insurance document templates. (ASP.NET Core, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap)
- o Applied Relay: Regular commits made toward Applied Belfast's flagship insurance pricing and management software, plus satellite web and desktop applications. (C#, .NET, ASP.NET, WinForms)

First Central Insurance & Technology Group

Haywards Heath, UK

Statistical Analyst/Data Scientist

Jan. 2019 - Oct. 2020

- Web scraping: Developed a collection of web scrapers to efficiently scrape, parse and merge large volumes of quote XMLs. (Python, xmltodict, json, BeautifulSoup)
- Machine learning: Built aggregator classification and renewal propensity models, plus dimensionality reduction and clustering notebooks using principal component analysis. (Python, Pandas, NumPy, scikit-learn, Matplotlib)
- Rating engine development: Greenfield development of an in-house insurance pricing engine written in Willis Towers Watson's proprietary scripting language, plus a GBM-based model optimisation framework.

Brighton, UK

Bartender, Mitchells & Butlers; Statistical Analyst, InterAnalysis

Sep. 2017 - Apr. 2018, Jul. 2016 - Aug. 2016

EDUCATION

Imperial College London

London, UK

Master of Science in Applied Mathematics; Distinction (76%)

Oct. 2016 - Oct. 2018

• Research project: Developed a genetic algorithm in C++ that simulates tumour growth in two and three dimensional space, based on a mathematical model of evolutionary ecology (88%).

University of Sussex

Brighton, UK

Bachelor of Science in Mathematics; First Class Honours (89%)

Sep. 2013 - May 2016 Brighton, UK

Cardinal Newman Sixth Form College A Levels; Mathematics (A*), Physics (A), Chemistry (B), plus the Extended Project (A)

2011 - 2013

HarvardX: Harvard University's Online Course Facility

Online

CS50 Introduction to Computer Science, Verified Track; Distinction (93%)

Sep. 2017 - Jul. 2018

o Coverage: A 12 week course covering data structures and algorithms, software development in C, plus web development using Python (Flask), JavaScript, HTML and CSS.